Muzhe Wu

J 734-358-7357 | ► henrw@umich.edu | ★ henrw.github.io
G github.com/henrw | ★ @MuzheW | In linkedin.com/in/muzhe-wu-573920223/

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest is in the intersection of artificial intelligence and human-computer interaction. I am specifically interested in creating interpretable and generalizable intelligent systems/agents that can learn from humans' behaviors and respond in alignment with humans' intents.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2021 - Apr 2023 (Expected)

• Advisors: Anhong Guo, Xu Wang, Veronica Perez-Rosas

• GPA: 3.95/4.00

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Shanghai, China

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sept 2019 - Aug 2023 (Expected)

• GPA: 3.76/4.00 (ranked 21th out of 252 students in the class)

PUBLICATIONS, PRESENTATIONS & POSTERS

2022 <u>Muzhe Wu</u>*, Haocheng Ren*, Gregory Croisdale, Xu Wang, Anhong Guo. "Rubikon: A Multimodal Tutor for 3D Physical Task Learning." *Michigan Al Symposium 2022.* Poster Presentation & Demo. [Best Demo Award]

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Towards Understanding the Relation between Misinformation and Engagement | NLP

Jul 2022 - Present

LIT Lab (UMich) - Advisor: Veronica Perez-Rosas

- Designed a highly interpretable pipeline for online video engagement rating consisting of multimodal (visual, audio and textual) data preprocessing, mid-level feature extraction, time alignment, and an unbalanced early fusion model;
- Formally defined and labeled the engagement rate for the YouTube Prostate Cancer Dataset of 250 videos; trained the pipeline and performed a comparative study on the relation between misinformation and engagement.

MineDojo | RL Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

Jim-Team (NVIDIA) - Advisor: Jim Fan

- Enabled GPU acceleration for scalable MineDojo RL simulation on headless machines by investigating EGL docker image;
- Created a meta-dataset of 20 open-ended, task-oriented datasets; scraped web data (e.g., GitHub repos for front-end development frameworks, DALL-E-2 showcase) to construct knowledge bases for generalist agent training.

Multimodal Cognitive Tutor | HCI

May 2022 - Present

HAIL Lab, Lifelong Learning Lab (UMich) - Advised by Xu Wang, Anhong Guo

- Designed a new ITS framework that leverages AI and AR and augments current tutorial methods for 3D physical tasks;
- Build the system for the Rubik's Cube learning, featuring domain/user modeling (by parsing and analyzing multimodal input, e.g., finger detection and ArUco markers), adaptive feedback (based on the abstractive knowledge tree and user/system initiatives), new task generation and low cognitive load guidance (voice aid, hidden side revelation, and spatial arrow).

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

2021, 2022 **Dean's Honor List** at the University of Michigan

2021 Mathematical Contest in Modeling Meritorious Winner Prize (<9.5%)

2020 University Physics Competition Silver Award (<3%)

2019, 2020 **Undergraduate Excellent Scholarship** at Shanghai Jiao Tong University (<10%)

SELECTED PROJECTS

Auxiliary Variables Improve Group Accuracy without Group Information [Link]

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

- Validated the effectiveness of auxiliary variables in the first stage of the JTT algorithm resolving the spurious correlation in ML;
- Designed, recreated, and collected visual datasets for spurious correlation research (e.g., configurable MNIST-CIFAR10).

FAD: Feature Alignment Discriminator for Text Summarization [Link]

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

- Introduced a BERT-based discriminator to BART text generator and designed feature alignment mechanism; achieved SOTA
 performance on CNN/DailyMail dataset for automatic abstractive text summarization.
- Trained the model with different settings (rDrop, layers used as features, and hyper-parameters) and compared it with baseline models (e.g., fine-tuned BART-base model) on ROUGE score.

Retro Game API for Reinforcement Learning [Link]

Feb 2022

- Developed an API for retro game simulation with reinforcement learning focus.
- Applied *gym-retro* integration tools to build runnable ROMs; designed a simulation environment with regulation methods and compatible utility classes (recorder, interactor, and dataset); designed a simulation GUI with observation and state information visualized; implemented wrapper classes for vision transform (random cropping, random convolution, and gaussian noise).

Mask Distribution Simulator [Link]

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020

- Created a C++ program that evaluates the number of masks needed by cities in Hubei Province during the COVID-19 period and simulated the transportation of masks within the province along with subsequent impacts on pandemic situations.
- Applied the SIR model to classify people into different groups; set up parameters per factors including mask numbers and social distance; designed an interactive GUI that displays simulation results with OpenGL.

COMPETITIONS

Mathematical Contest in Modeling | Meritorious Winner Prize

Feb 2021

- Modeled an ecosystem of different types of fungi (competitive relationships) with limited nutrients and simulated their long-term growth trends in various weather conditions.
- Applied Competitive Lotka Volterra Equations to formulate differential equations of fungi's growth; formulated correlation
 factors with geometry and necessary simplifications; evaluated weather factors with linear regression method; visualized
 simulation results in diagrams with MATLAB and Python.

University Physics Competition | Silver Medal

Nov 2020

- Formulated the route for a lightweight spacecraft traveling from earth to Saturn at the minimum fuel cost.
- Applied physics models, e.g., Conservation of Momentum, Kepler's Law, and Hohmann Transfer Orbit, to calculate the optimal track; established the relationships between fuel consumption and weight, distance, and time with Euler's Method.

SKILLS & RELATED COURSES

SKILLS

Languages Python, C/C++, Java, Javascript, SQL, C#, MATLAB, R, Verilog **Frameworks** PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, SwiftUI, React, Vue, Scrapy, Flask, Bootstrap

Tools ETFX, Unity, Mathematica, HTML, Figma, Linux (Ubuntu), Solidworks, Adobe Creative Suite

RELATED COURSES

ML/NLP/CV Machine Learning; Natural Language Processing; Computer Vision; Science of Deep Learning;

User Interface Development; Human-Centered ML; Mind & Machine;

Other CS Web Systems; Operating Systems; Computer Organization; Data Structures & Algorithms;

Computer Security; Computer Science Foundations & Pragmatics;

Math Multivariable & Vector Calculus; Linear Algebra; Differential Equations; Discrete Math; Probability & Statistics;

EE Electrical Circuits; Signals & Systems; Logic Design; Analog Circuits;

VOLUNTEER & EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

Ann Arbor Figure Skating Club

June 2022 - Present

Competed and volunteered in adult figure skating competitions in Ann Arbor.

SJTU Basketball Association

Aug 2020 – Aug 2021

Organized and refereed in collegial basketball matches at Shanghai Jiao Tong University.

High School Advisory

May 2020

Advised on the College Entrance Examination preparation for (\approx 700) senior students in Wenzhou No. 2 Foreign Language School.

UMJI Voluntary Association

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

Regularly visited Jiangchuan Sunshine nursing house, hosting events and caring for people with mental difficulties.

REFERENCES

Anhong Guo
Assistant Professor
Department of CSE
University of Michigan

⊠ anhong@umich.edu (personal website) Xu Wang

Linxi "Jim" Fan

Research Scientist
Al Research
NVIDIA

☑ linxif@nvidia.com
(personal website)

Verónica Pérez-Rosas